PROFILE

I specialize in create functional and aesthetic experiences for web and mobile apps centered design human, high fidelity prototyping and icons design lover. Over 8 years of experiences working on projects of a broad range of fields.

Spanish: Native English: Limited

EXPERIENCE

frog Sr. Interaction Designer 2020 - Now | Remote

- Relevant experience: CUNA Mutual Group: Loan Officer Experience, Forever21, GE (Energy).
- Tasks included: design system, interaction design, interface design, prototyping, microinteraction and handoff.

23 Design Visual and Interaction Designer 2018 - 2020 | Hybrid

- Relevant experience: Bitso App via 23 Design (2018), Credilikeme via 23 Design (2019).
- Tasks included: interaction design, interface design, prototyping, micro-interaction, design system and handoff.

gluo Interaction Designer 2017 - 2018 | On site

· Tasks included: interaction design, interface design, prototyping and handoff.

EDUCATION

The Interaction Design Foundation (Online) 2020 - Now

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Interaction Design for Usability

Platzi 2014 - 2017

- Career Product Design & UX
- Product Design by Aerolab

BUAP 2010 - 2014

- · Bachelor Degree in Graphic Design
- · Audiovisual design specialization.

TEACHING

Domestika: Ul Kit Creation with Sketch (Online Course) - Teacher 2021 - Now

 Planning, recording and teaching how to create UI Kits in Sketch using the Atomic Design methodology.

Sketch: Sketch&Design Meetup - Co-organizer & Speaker 2017 - 2020

 Organizing meetup and giving talks on: Atomic Design, Design System, Handoff, Version Control, Prototyping.

SKILLS

- · Wireframing
- Detail design
- HTML Knowledge

- Design processProduct focused
- Prototyping Motion design
- CSS KnowledgeJS Knowledge

TOOLS STACK

• Figma

- Webflow
- Artboard

- · Sketch
- Protopie
- Rive

- Framer
- Principle
- and more